# **Edward Byrnes**

Mult Func Engrg & Sci Asc Mgr

Audubon, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Edward-Byrnes/f443d2eec610bcb8

32 years of experience in technical projects for Lockheed Martin / Martin Marietta / General Electric. Significant leadership experience including program and project management, functional management at both unit and second line levels, and Integrated Project Team leadership across multiple contractors. Experienced at recruiting and retaining talent for hard-to-fill openings requiring unique specialized skills. Broad technical experience across multiple program phases including study, development, and operations. Experienced in development and management of Agile programs. Strong history with proposal development. Highly proficient in program finance including Earned Value Management, budget planning and oversight with a particular skill in creation and tracking of staffing and financial metrics using advanced Excel techniques, databases, and ERP systems. Strong Systems Engineering, Integration, and Test background. Excellent communications skills. Experience base includes contracts with multiple government agencies and a current DoD Top Secret clearance with SCI access and a current SSBI. Bachelor's and Master's degrees in Electrical Engineering from Villanova University.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Mult Func Engrg & Sci Asc Mgr

Lockheed Martin Integrated Systems and Global Solutions - Defense & Intelligence Solutions - King of Prussia, PA - January 2014 to February 2016

King of Prussia, PA

Mult Func Engrg & Sci Asc Mgr

Leadership and functional management supporting multiple programs across the country. Responsible for employee recruitment, hiring and training, performance assessment, promotions, work assignments, career development, leadership assessment, salary, and recognition/disciplinary actions. As a leader, provide additional support to senior management in recruiting and staffing, including direct support to college staffing events and ensuring timely status and closure of critical staffing needs.

#### **Systems Engineering Manager**

Lockheed Martin Integrated Systems and Global Solutions - Defense - King of Prussia, PA - April 2011 to December 2013

Systems Engineering leadership providing technical leadership and functional management for 28 full and part time employees servicing multiple contracts. Responsible for employee recruitment, selection and training, performance assessment, work assignments, salary, and recognition/disciplinary actions. On program, responsible for a variety of leadership tasking including Agile Scrum Master and Program Management tasks such as long range staffing planning, budget maintenance, schedule maintenance and senior customer contact.

#### **Engineering Program Manager - BADLANDS program**

Lockheed Martin Integrated Systems and Global Solutions - Defense - King of Prussia, PA - April 2007 to July 2012

King of Prussia, PA

Engineering Program Manager - BADLANDS program

Run day to day operations on a \$7 million per year, 30+ head operational program with elements in Valley Forge PA and Colorado Springs CO. Accountable to director for staffing and retention for multiple contracts, by working closely with other Engineering Program Managers in the same business area to share common resources. Accountable to the Director for meeting contract orders, sales, profit, and cash commitments on a monthly, quarterly and annual basis. Responsible for budgeting and planning the program baseline, and driving performance as the Cost Accountability Manager. Develop, tailor, and maintain engineering and program management processes and standard operating procedures. Develop and pursue organic sales growth opportunities with the customer. Maintain a strong working relationship with prime contractor Program Manager. Act for LM Program Manager as required.

#### SEIT Lead - Program 713

Lockheed Martin IS&S Intelligence Systems - King of Prussia, PA - November 2003 to April 2007

System Engineering, Integration and Test lead on an aggressively paced, highly successful development program from program startup through deployment and operational phase. Led all format design phase efforts on behalf of the prime contractor. Cost Accountability Manager for SEIT and PM teams. System Requirements lead for all contractors. System, segment and intersegment verification lead, with significant prime contractor and government customer direct Program Management contact. After system deployment, led effort for data collection and analysis of system demonstration with direct daily contact with the government customer, acting for the prime contractor. This effort was the sole award fee criteria for the period and resulted in a 100% award fee plus rollover fee. This period included 4 months as Acting Program Manager.

#### **Systems Integration**

Lockheed Martin Management and Data Systems - King of Prussia, PA - October 2000 to November 2003

Deputy Program Manager/Acting Program Manager, Program 677

Responsible for daily operations of a \$20M, 80+ FTE Systems Integration program for a national customer in satellite communications. Included 1 year as Acting Program Manager and second line manager for all 80 employees. Represented Washington DC-based Program Manager in Valley Forge region. Responsible for staffing, planning, program execution, meeting budget constraints, meeting orders, sales, profit, and cash commitments. Regular customer Program Manager contact. Directed Engineering Change Proposals to the program. Chaired Engineering Review Board.

#### Systems Integration

GE/Martin Marietta/Lockheed Martin Management and Data Systems - King of Prussia, PA - October 1988 to October 2000

Systems Engineer, Program 605/607/668/677

Multiple system engineer roles at System, Segment, and Subsystem levels in support of a large systems integration effort for a national customer in satellite communications. Effort included roles as spacecraft controls subsystem lead, unit manager, and second line manager.

### **Production Engineer, MK21 Program**

General Electric Company ReEntry Systems - Philadelphia, PA - June 1983 to October 1988

Designed components for Solid State Radar element of the Arming and Fuzing Assembly of the MX (Peacekeeper) Missile. Performed detailed circuit analysis and documentation. Designed and developed test equipment. Performed unit level testing, troubleshooting and disposition of production units.

**EDUCATION** 

#### Masters in Electrical Engineering

Villanova University - Villanova, PA September 1983 to May 1989

## **Bachelors in Electrical Engineering**

Villanova University - Villanova, PA September 1979 to May 1983

SKILLS

Project Management (10+ years)